Preliminary Guide to the Vice President for Information and Administration Services records, 1945-1998 RG0021
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Vice President for Information and Administration Services records
1945-1998
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Mangum, Edward
George Washington University. Office of the Vice President for Information and Administration Services
RG0021
2.25 Linear Feet
Materials in this collection include correspondence, manuscripts, article, and brochures. They range in date from 1945-98, and were transferred to the University Archives by the Vice President for Information and Administration Services.
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
Materials were transferred to the University Archives by the Vice President for Information and Administration Services.
Historical or Biographical Note
The Vice President for Information and Administration Services of The George Washington University reports to the President, and originally oversaw the Graphics and Printing Department, the Lisner Auditorium, Telecommunications, Human Resources, Registrar's Office, University Relations, Computer Information and Resource Center, and University Special Events.
It became the Office of Vice President of Administration and Information Service around 2001, when a Vice President for Communications was created. The VP for Communications now oversees Graphics and Printing, Lisner Auditorium, University Relations, and University Special Events. It also overseas the Media and Public Affairs Building.
N.B. This history note was written in 2005
Collection Scope and Content
Materials in this collection include correspondence, manuscripts, article, and brochures. They range in date from 1945-98, and were transferred to the University Archives by the Vice President for Information and Administration Services.
Collection Organization
Organized in three series: Office files, World War II 50th anniversary, and Papers and correspondence of Edward Mangum.
Washington (D.C.); Theater; World War, 1939-1945; Arena Stage (Organization: Washington, D.C.); George Washington University
- Office files, 1949-1998; RG0021 Series 1; 0.25 Linear feet (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains correspondence, memorandums, guides, brochures, manuals, postcards, and reports. They range in date from 1949-1998.
  Formerly vertical files
  - Administration and Staff, 1949-1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Administration and Staff - Guide to Academic Administrative Procedures for Deans and Chairmen, circa 1962 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Graphics and Printing, Office of, circa 1972-12/3 /1998 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- World War II 50th anniversary, 1995; RG0021 Series 2; 1.5 Linear feet (Box 1)
  This series contains correspondence (including with Colin Powell) and a commemorative flag from the 50th anniversary of the end of World War II in 1995.
  Formerly ACC#581
  - WWII Commemorative Flag, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letter from Charles J. Kramer, Department of the Army, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    General note
    Notification that GW was chosen as a WWII Commemorative Community
  - Letter from Lynn Shipway: Visit to Pentagon for flag presentation, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letter from Executive Director, Department of Defense, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Regarding the display of the Commemorative flag
  - Letter from Colin Powell to President Trachtenberg, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Acceptance of invitation to be at flag presentation
  - Letter from President Trachtenberg to Powell, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Invitation to be at flag presentation
  - Letter from Lt. General Claude M. Kicklighter, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Dates for the flag presentation
  - Letter from Lynn Shipway to President Trachtenberg, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Presentation of flag specifics and people
- Papers and correspondence of Edward Mangum, 1945-1998; RG0021 Series 3; 0.5 Linear feet (Box 1)
  This series contains papers and correspondence of Edward Mangum, a faculty member at The George Washington University and co-founder of Washington, D.C.'s Arena Stage. They date from 1945 to 1998. See also an article in "Washington History" (call number F191.C72; v.10:1).
  Formerly ACC#651
  - Manuscript, "Birth of A Theatre: Original Arena Stage Emerges from Church Cocoon", 1998 (Box 1, Folder 1.1)
    for Washington History: Magazine of the Historical Society of Washington D.C.
  - Correspondence, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 1.2)
  - Prospectus for the Washington Drama Center which would include Center Stage-a theater for Washington, D.C., 1958 (Box 1, Folder 1.3)
  - By George article, "President Clinton honors GW alumna Fichandler: Arena Stage founder Zelda Fichandler receives National Medal of Arts.", 02/1997 (Box 1, Folder 1.5)
  - Letter from Mangum to President Trachtenberg explaining his creation of the Arena Stage, 05/12/1997 (Box 1, Folder 2.1)
  - By George article, "President Clinton honors GW alumna Fichandler: Arena Stage founder Zelda Fichandler receives National Medal of Arts.", 02/1997 (Box 1, Folder 2.2)
  - Printed article by Edward Mangum, "Washington's Arena Stage Emerges from Church Cocoon,", 1998 (Box 1, Folder 2.3)
  - Washington Times article, "Syracuse Theater hires Arena Associate", 06/16/1992 (Box 1, Folder 2.4)
  - Washington Post article, "Geppetto of Foggy Bottom", 08/27/1978 (Box 1, Folder 2.5)
  - Washington Post article, "Washington Before Barry-And After", 05/23/1998 (Box 1, Folder 2.6)
  - Various correspondence and articles, undated (Box 1, Folder 2.7)
  - Article by Edward Mangum, "Toward a Living Theater", 1949 (Box 1, Folder 3.1)
  - Library of Congress Information Bulletin partially about GWU drama students performing "Our American Cousin" a play about the assassination of Abraham Lincoln, 05/08/1950 (Box 1, Folder 3.2)
    Mangum played the part of Lincoln
  - Cast Memorabilia, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 3.3)
  - Photocopied images of "Noah" a play performed by GW students in the 1950's., undated (Box 1, Folder 3.4)
  - Article from Times Herald, "G.W. Players Revive A Fine Folk Play, 'Dark of the Moon'", 04/24/1948 (Box 1, Folder 3.5)
    staged by Edward Mangum
  - Information on The Mount Vernon Players, 1945-1947 (Box 1, Folder 3.6)
  - Article by Edward Mangum, "Shakespeare in Shirt Sleeves" printed in Players Magazine: Serving the Educational Theater, 03/1948 (Box 1, Folder 3.7)
  - Correspondence and photos, 1945-1949 (Box 1, Folder 3.8)
  - List from Arena Stage of the plays produced from August 1950-May 1952, 08/1950-05/1952 (Box 1, Folder 4.1)
  - Arena Stage articles, 1950-1952 (Box 1, Folder 4.2)
  - Article from The Church School, "The Mount Vernon Players", 09/1964 (Box 1, Folder 4.3)
  - Correspondence, 05/08/1991 (Box 1, Folder 4.4)